{
 "title": "Harry Potter!",
 "listOfQuestions": [
 { "question": "What is the name of the first book in the Harry Potter series?",
 "correctAnswer": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets", "Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban", "Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire"] },
 { "question": "Who is Harry Potter's best friend?",
 "correctAnswer": "Ron Weasley",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Hermione Granger", "Neville Longbottom", "Draco Malfoy"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the magical sport played on broomsticks in the Harry Potter series?",
 "correctAnswer": "Quidditch",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Infernal Quidditch", "Quizzle", "Broomstruck"] },
 { "question": "What house is known for its bravery and courage at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry?",
 "correctAnswer": "Gryffindor",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Ravenclaw", "Hufflepuff", "Slytherin"] },
 { "question": "Who is the headmaster of Hogwarts throughout most of the series?",
 "correctAnswer": "Albus Dumbledore",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Severus Snape", "Gilderoy Lockhart", "Remus Lupin"] },
 { "question": "What magical object allows Harry to see into the memories of others?",
 "correctAnswer": "Pensieve",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Time-Turner", "Sneakoscope", "Remembrall"] },
 { "question": "What type of creature is Dobby?",
 "correctAnswer": "House-elf",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Goblin", "Werewolf", "Basilisk"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the prison guarded by Dementors in the wizarding world?",
 "correctAnswer": "Azkaban",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Nurmengard", "Alcatraz", "Arkham Asylum"] },
 { "question": "What is Harry's Patronus charm in the shape of?",
 "correctAnswer": "Stag",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Otter", "Phoenix", "Werewolf"] },
 { "question": "Who is the half-giant teacher of Care of Magical Creatures?",
 "correctAnswer": "Rubeus Hagrid",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Gilderoy Lockhart", "Argus Filch", "Sybill Trelawney"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the three-headed dog guarding the Philosopher's Stone?",
 "correctAnswer": "Fluffy",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Fang", "Norbert", "Aragog"] },
 { "question": "What type of dragon does Harry face in the Triwizard Tournament?",
 "correctAnswer": "Hungarian Horntail",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Chinese Fireball", "Swedish Short-Snout", "Peruvian Vipertooth"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the dark wizard who killed Harry's parents?",
 "correctAnswer": "Lord Voldemort",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Bellatrix Lestrange", "Gellert Grindelwald", "Salazar Slytherin"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the magical object that can make any drink appear in front of the drinker?",
 "correctAnswer": "The Room of Requirement",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Floo Powder", "Portkey", "Peruvian Instant Darkness Powder"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the elf who serves the Malfoy family?",
 "correctAnswer": "Kreacher",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Dobby", "Winky", "Hokey"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of Hermione's magical cat?",
 "correctAnswer": "Crookshanks",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Mrs. Norris", "Pigwidgeon", "Firenze"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the Weasley's magical flying car?",
 "correctAnswer": "Ford Anglia",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Knight Bus", "Hogwarts Express", "Thestral Cart"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the wizarding village near Hogwarts School?",
 "correctAnswer": "Hogsmeade",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Diagon Alley", "Godric's Hollow", "Little Whinging"] },
 { "question": "Who is Harry's godfather?",
 "correctAnswer": "Sirius Black",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Remus Lupin", "James Potter", "Peter Pettigrew"] },
 { "question": "What type of spell can repel a Dementor?",
 "correctAnswer": "Expecto Patronum",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Stupefy", "Expelliarmus", "Alohomora"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the potion that allows the drinker to transform into someone else?",
 "correctAnswer": "Polyjuice Potion",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Felix Felicis", "Veritaserum", "Amortentia"] },
 { "question": "What is the core of Harry's wand made of?",
 "correctAnswer": "Phoenix feather",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Dragon heartstring", "Unicorn hair", "Thestral tail hair"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of Gilderoy Lockhart's tragic autobiography?",
 "correctAnswer": "Magical Me",
 "wrongAnswers": ["One Flew Over the Hippogriff's Nest", "Charmingly Conceited", "Fantastic Beasts and How to Avoid Them"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the gamekeeper and Care of Magical Creatures professor at Hogwarts?",
 "correctAnswer": "Rubeus Hagrid",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Remus Lupin", "Alastor Moody", "Sybill Trelawney"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the house elf who serves the Malfoy family?",
 "correctAnswer": "Dobby",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Kreacher", "Winky", "Hokey"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of Harry Potterâ€™s group of loyal friends who help him challenge Lord Voldemort and fight the Death Eaters?",
 "correctAnswer": "Dumbledore's Army",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Gryffindor's Pride", "The Order of the Phoenix", "The Marauders"] },
 { "question": "What is Hermione's Patronus charm in the shape of?",
 "correctAnswer": "Otter",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Stag", "Phoenix", "Werewolf"] },
 { "question": "What is the wands are made of?",
 "correctAnswer": "Wood and core materials",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Wood and vines", "Metal and core materials", "Plastic and core materials"] },
 { "question": "The Deluminator, also known as the Put-Outer, is a device in the Harry Potter series that has multiple functions. How does it work?",
 "correctAnswer": "The Deluminator can remove sources of light to darken a room and captures and releases light from one source to another",
 "wrongAnswers": ["It removes the memory from one person's brain", "It makes things levitate", "It opens doors"] },
 { "question": "Peter Pettigrew and the nickname Wormtail. Name the other nicknames from the Marauder's Map.",
 "correctAnswer": "Prongs, Moony, Padfoot",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Hobbit, Elf, Dwarf", "Mad-Eye, Tonks, Wormtail", "Snape, Lockhart, Skeeter"] },
 { "question": "Who possesses the power of invisibility cloak in Harry Potter series?",
 "correctAnswer": "Harry Potter",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Ron Weasley", "Hermione Granger", "Dobby"] },
 { "question": "What is the Forbidden Forest?",
 "correctAnswer": "A forest within the grounds of Hogwarts School that has a bad reputation. Many dangerous creatures live or lurk there, and many challenges are set for students, such as detention or Care of Magical Creatures lessons.",
 "wrongAnswers": ["It's a forest where people can picnic", "A magical party forest", "For students of forbidden ages"] },
 { "question": "With which house does Draco Malfoy share a dormitory?",
 "correctAnswer": "Slytherin",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Gryffindor", "Hufflepuff", "Ravenclaw"] },
 { "question": "Who is the Divination professor at Hogwarts?",
 "correctAnswer": "Sybill Trelawney",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Firenze", "Pomona Sprout", "Cuthbert Binns"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the house elf who dies in the service of Bellatrix Lestrange?",
 "correctAnswer": "Dobby",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Kreacher", "Winky", "Hokey"] },
 { "question": "What drink can help a person recover from consuming poison?",
 "correctAnswer": "Bezoar",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Veritaserum", "Polyjuice Potion", "Felix Felicis"] },
 { "question": "Name the Weasley twins.",
 "correctAnswer": "Fred and George",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Bill and Charlie", "Percy and Ron", "Ginny and Hermione"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the magical map that shows the location and movements of individuals within Hogwarts?",
 "correctAnswer": "The Marauder's Map",
 "wrongAnswers": ["The Quidditch Pitch Map", "The Hogwarts Guide", "The Defense Against the Dark Arts Map"] },
 { "question": "Who teaches Defense Against the Dark Arts in Harry's sixth year at Hogwarts?",
 "correctAnswer": "Severus Snape",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Dolores Umbridge", "Gilderoy Lockhart", "Remus Lupin"] },
 { "question": "Who kills Albus Dumbledore in the Harry Potter series?",
 "correctAnswer": "Severus Snape",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Bellatrix Lestrange", "Draco Malfoy", "Voldemort"] },
 { "question": "Which Horcrux was destroyed last?",
 "correctAnswer": "Nagini",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Helga Hufflepuff's Cup", "Tom Riddle's Diary", "Rowena Ravenclaw's Diadem"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the wizard who created the Sorcerer's Stone?",
 "correctAnswer": "Nicholas Flamel",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Gellert Grindelwald", "Albus Dumbledore", "Sven Sixkiller"] },
 { "question": "What is the real name of Mad-Eye Moody?",
 "correctAnswer": "Alastor Moody",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Barty Crouch Jr.", "Kingsley Shacklebolt", "Ernie Macmillan"] },
 { "question": "Who is the head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement in the Ministry of Magic?",
 "correctAnswer": "Amelia Bones",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Cornelius Fudge", "Pius Thicknesse", "Rufus Scrimgeour"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the spell used to disarm an opponent?",
 "correctAnswer": "Expelliarmus",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Stupefy", "Avada Kedavra", "Alohomora"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the wizard who takes over as Defense Against the Dark Arts professor at Hogwarts after Gilderoy Lockhart?",
 "correctAnswer": "Remus Lupin",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Dolores Umbridge", "Severus Snape", "Barty Crouch Jr."] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the potion that Dumbledore drinks in 'The Half-Blood Prince'?",
 "correctAnswer": "The Drink of Despair",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Felix Felicis", "Veritaserum", "Amortentia"] },
 { "question": "Who does Harry see in the Mirror of Erised?",
 "correctAnswer": "His parents",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Himself as a famous Quidditch player", "A future version of himself", "He doesn't see anyone"] },
 { "question": "What is the Hogwarts school motto?",
 "correctAnswer": "Draco dormiens nunquam titillandus (Never tickle a sleeping dragon)",
 "wrongAnswers": ["It's not very important", "The light will show you the way", "Peace, unity, happiness"] },
 { "question": "What is the name of the ghost who haunts the girls' bathrooms at Hogwarts?",
 "correctAnswer": "Moaning Myrtle",
 "wrongAnswers": ["Nearly Headless Nick", "The Bloody Baron", "The Fat Friar"] }
 ]
}
